<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>service fabric on Noel Bundick</title><link>/tags/service-fabric/</link><description>Recent content in service fabric on Noel Bundick</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 15:56:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/service-fabric/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running Windows Containers with Volumes on Azure Service Fabric</title><link>/posts/running-windows-containers-with-volumes-on-azure-service-fabric/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 15:56:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/running-windows-containers-with-volumes-on-azure-service-fabric/</guid><description>Containers are rapidly becoming the de-facto choice for application packaging, distribution, and execution in the cloud. This newfound flexibility brings new challenges, particularly with stateful workloads like databases. With the advent of container orchestrators, it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a safe assumption that the underlying data for your server is already directly connected to your host. Nodes fail and are dynamically scaled, but your app still needs its data.
Azure Service Fabric is a distributed systems platform that added support for containers a while back.</description></item><item><title>Service Fabric Cluster Quickstart</title><link>/posts/service-fabric-cluster-quickstart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 12:22:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/service-fabric-cluster-quickstart/</guid><description>With the latest round of updates released at Build 2017, Service Fabric has become more powerful than ever, and getting started is now a breeze. This quick guide will help you get started with a secure Service Fabric cluster that you can start tinkering with.
Prerequisites 🔗 Azure subscription Azure PowerShell TL;DR install: run Install-Module AzureRM in a PowerShell window Creating a cluster 🔗Get started with a new PowerShell window. Running the following commands will automatically create all the required Azure resources on your behalf and will output a ton of great info about your newly created cluster.</description></item></channel></rss>