<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>minecraft on Noel Bundick</title><link>/tags/minecraft/</link><description>Recent content in minecraft on Noel Bundick</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 15:56:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/minecraft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Running Windows Containers with Volumes on Azure Service Fabric</title><link>/posts/running-windows-containers-with-volumes-on-azure-service-fabric/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 15:56:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/running-windows-containers-with-volumes-on-azure-service-fabric/</guid><description>Containers are rapidly becoming the de-facto choice for application packaging, distribution, and execution in the cloud. This newfound flexibility brings new challenges, particularly with stateful workloads like databases. With the advent of container orchestrators, it&amp;rsquo;s no longer a safe assumption that the underlying data for your server is already directly connected to your host. Nodes fail and are dynamically scaled, but your app still needs its data.
Azure Service Fabric is a distributed systems platform that added support for containers a while back.</description></item><item><title>Fun with Azure Container Instances</title><link>/posts/fun-with-azure-container-instances/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 17:32:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/fun-with-azure-container-instances/</guid><description>Fun with Azure Container Instances 🔗Azure Container Instances were recently announced, making it easy for developers to spin up a container on-demand without having to provision and maintain a VM or a cluster. It&amp;rsquo;s been well received by the community, and there are already a ton of great resources to help you get started.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not what this post is about! 🔗Truthfully, I can only sit through so many canned docker run nginx demos.</description></item></channel></rss>